Malcolm Johnson

(314) 224-9696 malcolmtosh.com malcolmdjohnson@gmail.com

Summary

UX and visual designer with 10+ years of experience across FinTech, automotive, food, retail, and non-profit. Skilled in creating user-centered designs, improving workflows, and refining digital experiences. Experienced in collaborating with engineers, researchers, and product teams to build functional, intuitive interfaces.

Skills

UX/UI design
Visual design
Interaction design
Wireframing
Prototyping
WCAG standards
Journey mapping
User personas

Tools

Figma
Sketch
InVision
Adobe XD
Photoshop
Illustrator
InDesign
HTML/CSS/JavaScript

Research

Usability testing
A/B testing
Qualitative & quantitative
data analysis
Competitive analysis
WEVO

Experience

Senior UX Designer | Mastercard

November 2021 — Present

- Took ownership of Mastercard's first-ever B2C UI Kit, evolving it beyond its initial agency-built version.
- Standardized and expedited design refreshes across 90+ regional Mastercard.com sites.
- Projected 57% reduction in design and engineering time through streamlined design processes.
- Saved an estimated \$70K by creating support pages in-house, with anticipated multi-million-dollar savings across regions.
- Improved accessibility compliance, mitigating potential fines and enhancing inclusivity.

UX/UI Designer | H&L Partners

March 2020 — November 2021

- Served as the agency's sole UX designer, leading research initiatives that improved user satisfaction by 25%.
- Designed and tested landing pages and email campaigns, increasing conversion rates by 40% and reducing bounce rates by 20%.
- Created user flows, wireframes, mockups, and clickable prototypes for automotive, healthcare, retail, and food brands, accelerating time-to-market.
- Built and animated web banners using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript (GSAP). Enhanced digital campaign performance, leading to a 30% increase in ad clickthrough rates.

Certifications

LinkedIn UX Design

- 1 Overview
- 2 Analyzing User Data
- 3 Creating Personas
- 4 Ideation
- 5 Scenarios/Storyboards
- 6 Paper Prototyping
- 7 Implementation Plan

LinkedIn Design Thinking

Understanding The Process
Implementing The

Process

LinkedIn UX Foundations

Information Architecture Multidevice Design Prototyping Style Guides and Design Systems

Bootcamp

Savvy Coders — Front-end Development Bootcamp

Education

Master's Degree

Advertising & Marketing Communications

Webster University

Bachelor's Degree

Marketing

Missouri State University

Experience

Designer | Ansira

April 2013 — March 2020

- Partnered with clients and account managers to create landing pages, emails, and ads that maintained brand consistency and improved customer engagement.
- Designed hyper-targeted ads for local markets that aligned with national campaigns, increasing regional conversion rates by 40%.
- Built, tested, and launched HTML5 web banners, improving click-through rates by 30% on average.

Volunteerism

Young Friends Board Member | Jazz St. Louis

August 2022 - August 2023

 Drove the mission of Jazz St. Louis to lead the community in advancing the art of jazz through live performance, education and outreach.

Communications Designer | AAF St. Louis

July 2021 — July 2022

- Designed digital and print assets to effectively communicate key messages, increasing awareness of the local advertising professional community.
- Modernized the American Advertising Federation
 St. Louis website, enhancing navigation, accessibility,
 and engagement for members and visitors.

Volunteer | Contemporary Art Museum St. Louis

February 2010 — September 2013

- Assisted in creating meaningful visitor experiences that foster curiosity, creativity, and learning.
- Provided logistical support for exhibitions, events, and educational programs, ensuring smooth execution and an engaging atmosphere for attendees.